<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-10-26T17:01:07+09:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Seungjun Lee</title><subtitle>AI research engineer specializing in deep generative models, anomaly detection, and medical image analysis. Published researcher in Nature Communications with expertise in machine learning and computer vision.</subtitle><author><name>Seungjun Lee</name></author><entry><title type="html">About</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/about/about/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="About" /><published>2023-10-05T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2023-10-05T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/about/about</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/about/about/"><![CDATA[<!-- TODO LIST:
- Update citations automatically. -->

<p><img src="/assets/images/about/profile.jpg" alt="Profile photo of Seungjun Lee" /></p>

<p>I am Seungjun Lee, an AI research engineer focused on advancing healthcare and engineering through innovative AI solutions. My expertise lies in deep generative models, anomaly detection, and medical image analysis.</p>

<h2 id="education">Education</h2>

<ul>
  <li>M.Sc. in Biomedical Engineering, University of Ulsan College of Medicine.</li>
  <li>B.S. in Naval Architecture and Ocean Engineering, Minor in Mechanical Engineering, Seoul National University.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="publications">Publications</h2>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Emergency Triage of Brain Computed Tomography via Anomaly Detection with a Deep Generative Model</strong> (2022). <em>Nature Communications</em>. <br />
Authors: <strong>Seungjun Lee</strong>, Boryeong Jeong, Minjee Kim, Ryoungwoo Jang, Wooyul Paik, Jiseon Kang, Won Jung Chung, Gil-Sun Hong, &amp; Namkug Kim.<br />
<a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-31808-0">Paper</a> | <a href="https://github.com/seungjunlee96/emergency-triage-of-brain-computed-tomography-via-anomaly-detection-with-a-deep-generative-model">Code</a>.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Deep Learning on Radar-Centric 3D Object Detection</strong> (2020). <em>arXiv preprint arXiv:2003.00851</em>. <br />
Author: <strong>Seungjun Lee</strong>.<br />
<a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2003.00851">Paper</a>.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Enhancement of Evaluating Flatfoot on a Weight-Bearing Lateral Radiograph of the Foot with U-Net Based Semantic Segmentation on the Long Axis of Tarsal and Metatarsal Bones</strong> (2022). <em>Computers in Biology and Medicine</em>. <br />
Authors: S.M. Ryu, K. Shin, S.W. Shin, <strong>Seungjun Lee</strong>, N. Kim.<br />
<a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0010482522000906">Paper</a>.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Enhancing Deep Learning Based Classifiers with Inpainting Anatomical Side Markers (L/R Markers) for Multi-Center Trials</strong> (2022). <em>Computer Methods and Programs in Biomedicine</em>.<br />
Authors: K.D. Kim, K. Cho, M. Kim, K.H. Lee, <strong>Seungjun Lee</strong>, S.M. Lee, K.H. Lee, N. Kim.<br />
<a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0169260722000906">Paper</a>.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Automated Idiopathic Normal Pressure Hydrocephalus Diagnosis via Artificial Intelligence–Based 3D T1 MRI Volumetric Analysis</strong> (2025). <em>American Journal of Neuroradiology</em>. <br />
Authors: Joonhyung Lee, Dana Kim, Chong Hyun Suh, Suyoung Yun, Kyu Sung Choi, <strong>Seungjun Lee</strong>, Wooseok Jung, Jinyoung Kim, Hwon Heo, Woo Hyun Shim, Sungyang Jo, Sun Ju Chung, Jae-Sung Lim, Ho Sung Kim, Sang Joon Kim, &amp; Jae-Hong Lee.<br />
<a href="https://www.ajnr.org/content/early/2025/01/02/ajnr.A8489">Paper</a>.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<h2 id="patents">Patents</h2>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Method of Detecting Anomaly Region in Medical Image, Anomaly Region Detection Device Performing Method, and Method of Training Neural Network Used to Detect Anomaly Region in Medical Image</strong>.<br />
Publication No. 1020220103852 A. Publication Date: July 25, 2022.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="recognitions">Recognitions</h2>

<ul>
  <li><strong>21st Pfizer Medical Research Award</strong> for contributions to emergency triage via anomaly detection <a href="https://www.medifonews.com/news/article.html?no=182863"></a>.</li>
  <li>Featured in <strong>BRIC - 한국을 빛내는 사람들</strong> <a href="https://www.ibric.org/bric/hanbitsa/han-interview.do?mode=view&amp;id=78947&amp;authorId=38395#!/list"></a>.</li>
  <li>Featured on <strong>AuntMinnie</strong>: “Deep-Learning Algorithm Triages Emergency Head CTs” <a href="https://www.auntminnie.com/index.aspx?sec=road&amp;sub=aic_2021&amp;pag=dis&amp;itemId=133994"></a>.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="professional-experience">Professional Experience</h2>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Research Scientist/Engineer</strong>, VUNO Inc. (March 2024 – Present).<br />
Contributing to AI-driven medical device development, including diagnostic tools for neuroimaging.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Machine Learning Engineer</strong>, MakinaRocks (June 2022 – March 2024).<br />
Developed and deployed ML models for industrial applications, focusing on anomaly detection and optimization.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Machine Learning Researcher</strong>, Asan Medical Center (March 2020 – June 2022).<br />
Conducted research on medical imaging AI, including generative models for diagnostic triage.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<h2 id="honors-and-awards">Honors and Awards</h2>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Best Presentation Award</strong>, Korean Society of Artificial Intelligence in Medicine (KoSAIM), for “Unsupervised Anomaly Detection with a Style-Based Generative Adversarial Network” (October 2020).</li>
  <li><strong>Minister of Trade, Industry and Energy Award</strong>, Creative Comprehensive Design Competition (December 2018).</li>
  <li><strong>Grand Prize</strong>, 7th Creative Design Festival, Seoul National University College of Engineering (September 2018).</li>
  <li><strong>Bronze Prize</strong>, 36th National Collegiate Mathematics Competition (Non-Mathematics Majors), Korean Mathematical Society (December 2017).</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>Seungjun Lee</name></author><category term="About" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>